<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/page/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>About</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/page/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/page/about/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to &lt;strong&gt;Marta&amp;rsquo;s BG Corner&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my little corner of the internet, dedicated to all things board games. Here I share my opinions, recent plays, and everything that fuels my passion for this incredible hobby. I don&amp;rsquo;t post on a fixed schedule, only when I have something I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely excited to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-little-about-me&#34;&gt;A Little About Me&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Marta, a Portuguese girl working in business intelligence, with a long-standing love for board games. For as long as I can remember, games have been part of my life. Growing up, playing cards, La Bonne Paye, and Monopoly were regular fixtures at home, and my family kept me well supplied with games throughout my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But my true passion, and my collection, really took off in 2018. My first purchase was Estoril, but the game that made me completely fall for the hobby was &lt;strong&gt;Pandemic Legacy: Season 1&lt;/strong&gt;. Even today, after around 1,000 plays of various games, it remains my best gaming experience. It was tense, intense, and absolutely unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve explored countless games across all kinds of mechanics. My favourites are Euro games and deckbuilders, though I&amp;rsquo;m always curious to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-youll-find-here&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Find Here&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog is a personal space, not a professional publication. You&amp;rsquo;ll find honest game reviews, recaps of my recent plays, convention reports, and whatever else catches my enthusiasm at the time. I write about games I&amp;rsquo;ve actually played, and I always try to give you my genuine take, the good and the bad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you share the same passion for board games, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll feel right at home here. 😊&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also find me on Mastodon: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@martasbgcorner&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;@martasbgcorner@mastodon.social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
