<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>January 2026 Plays</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post January 2026 Plays&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m bringing you my plays from January. This month had fewer total plays but more depth with individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2026 by the Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11 plays (compared to 17 in December)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 different games&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 new-to-me games&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most played: Welcome to the Moon (5 plays)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life was busy this month, which resulted in fewer plays overall. However, I enjoyed focusing more deeply on individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/games-stats-january.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;BG Stats of January&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;BG Stats of January&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-games-discovered&#34;&gt;New Games Discovered&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;wayfarers-of-the-south-tigris--1-play&#34;&gt;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/wayfarers.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – Setup&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – Setup&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are brave explorers, cartographers, and astronomers setting out from Baghdad to map the surrounding lands, sea, and sky. This 1-4 player game mixes several mechanics: worker placement, dice worker placement, set collection, and tile placement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this first play, particularly the construction of the panorama, the possible combos, and the need for medium to long-term planning. These elements create satisfying strategic depth and give you goals to work toward across multiple rounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I found the rulebook confusing. At first glance, it seems well-written, but when actually playing, I had difficulties finding answers to my questions. After a closer look, the rulebook organization feels muddled, making it hard to reference during play. I needed to return to the rules several times, which disrupted the flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I need to replay at least 2 more times before forming a complete opinion, but the core gameplay shows promise despite the rulebook issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;numbsters--1-play&#34;&gt;Numbsters – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/numbsters.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Numbsters – End of Game&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Numbsters – End of Game&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A solo small game that&amp;rsquo;s perfect to carry anywhere. No table space needed, you can hold the cards in your hand! The theme is &amp;ldquo;Hungry Numbers,&amp;rdquo; and it consists entirely of cards with beautifully designed numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal is to end with only the number 8 and one other card remaining. Crucially, the 8 must never be on top (the right side), you need the other card on top at the end, otherwise you lose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works: At the start of each round, you can either move one card or use the power of the rightmost card (or top card if holding them in your hand).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Eating Mechanic:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though it seems counterintuitive, smaller numbers eat bigger numbers! For a card to be eaten, the numbers must be sequential with the mouth card (the 8) in the middle. For example, if you have card 4, followed by 8, followed by 5, the 5 will be eaten because 4-5 are sequential around the 8.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 8 can never be eaten. However, if the 8 ends up on the right side (or on top when holding cards), you lose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Card Powers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Card powers can change the eating rules, some eat the smallest card, others the biggest, some target even numbers, etc. When using a power, you still need to eat a card adjacent to the 8, but the card whose power you&amp;rsquo;re using doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be adjacent, it just needs to be on the right side (or on top). After using a power, that card moves to the back (or left side).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked my first test. It&amp;rsquo;s really quick, easy to set up, and creates an interesting spatial puzzle. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bestseller, but I can see a lot of potential for travel or couch plays when you want a quick mental challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-i-continued-exploring&#34;&gt;Games I Continued Exploring&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;par-odin--1-play&#34;&gt;Par Odin – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/par-odin.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Par Odin&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Par Odin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a board game properly speaking, but rather a puzzle game. You have a set of figures represented by the sides of dice, and you need to split the dice into two groups where the sum of each group is equal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each character has different values and effects. For example, the ring removes 1 point from its group, while the mage has no point value itself but equals the sum of all white dice (non-mages) in the same group. These special effects add layers of complexity to what seems like a simple balancing puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really like this game when I want something quick that makes me think. The puzzles are satisfying to solve, and the special character abilities keep things interesting across different challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-moon--5-plays&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Moon – 5 plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/welcome-to-the-moon.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to The Moon – Adventure 4&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to The Moon – Adventure 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I played this 5 times this month and will probably continue. As I mentioned in my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/&#34; &gt;dedicated review&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign side with different scenarios telling a cohesive story is really enjoyable. The increasing difficulty is also very pleasant, keeping each adventure challenging and fresh. The narrative progression from ship preparation through to lunar mining operations continues to engage me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;merchants-cove--3-plays&#34;&gt;Merchants Cove – 3 plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/merchants-cove.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Merchants Cove and The Chronomancer with his assistant&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Merchants Cove and The Chronomancer with his assistant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asymmetric game where each player is a merchant creating and selling merchandise to people arriving in the city by boat. There are 4 types of customers who can request 2 different types of goods: biggest or smallest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solo Mode:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solo mode uses an automa managed by a set of cards. The goal is to beat the automa&amp;rsquo;s score, creating a competitive challenge even when playing alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants Tested:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyable testing each merchant. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested 6 merchants over time, I still have 5 to try! In solo mode, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested 3 merchants: the Alchemist, the Blacksmith, and the Chronomancer with his assistant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed playing each one, with the Chronomancer being my favorite of these three. He has the most creative mechanics, you travel across time and collect artifacts. You need to coordinate the two characters available as they have some constraints that create interesting puzzle moments. Managing both the Chronomancer and his assistant adds a unique strategic layer not present in the other merchants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write a full review for this game once I&amp;rsquo;ve tested more merchants and can speak comprehensively about the variety they offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-ahead-to-february&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead to February&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/&#34; &gt;December 2025 year-in-review&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned wanting to play Tapestry, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible in January. It will probably be played during the next month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of fun with these games and will certainly play them again soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What were your most-played games in January? Are you exploring games deeply or trying lots of new ones?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Welcome to the Moon: A Flip &amp; Write Campaign</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Welcome to the Moon: A Flip &amp; Write Campaign&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m taking you on a journey to the moon! Let me introduce you to &lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Moon&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a flip &amp;amp; write game with 8 interconnected adventures that can be played standalone or as a campaign. With reusable sheets and compact design, it offers tremendous replayability in a small package. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re preparing starships, programming flight paths, or establishing lunar colonies, each adventure brings unique challenges and mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a 2021 release for 1-6 players, ages 10+, with a playtime of 25-30 minutes. The game was designed by Alexis Allard and Benoit Turpin, illustrated by Anne Heidsieck, and published by Blue Cocker Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to the Moon box&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Welcome to the Moon, we&amp;rsquo;re called to colonize the moon as Earth is in bad shape. To succeed, we must first prepare our starship, program our path, and establish our lunar colony.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-it&#34;&gt;What Is It?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a flip &amp;amp; write game, you reveal cards (flipping them from a deck) and write numbers on your personal sheet based on what you draw. The twist? There are 8 different adventures, each with unique sheet designs and special rules, that can be played standalone or linked together in a campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The adventure guide has two modes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning mode&lt;/strong&gt; – Guides you through each adventure, as each has unique rules. The core mechanics remain the same, but the sheet designs mean numbers are placed differently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Campaign mode&lt;/strong&gt; – A connected narrative where each result influences the next adventure. Cards are hidden and revealed during gameplay, creating an evolving story.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 1&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;End of Adventure 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;components&#34;&gt;Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game includes 24 double-sided sheets (6 sheets with 2 scenarios each), 6 dry-erase pencils, starship cards, achievement cards, an adventure book with flavor text and setup instructions, and solo-specific cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/components.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to the Moon components&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Components&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;component-quality&#34;&gt;Component Quality&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major plus: instead of paper pads, the game uses reusable sheets compatible with dry-erase markers. This keeps the box compact and allows unlimited replays. The internal organizers are fantastic, keeping everything well organized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/sheets.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Erasable sheets&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Erasable Sheets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/organizers.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Box organizers&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Organizers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-plays&#34;&gt;How It Plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each round, you reveal cards showing number-action pairs. Choose one pair, write the number on your sheet following the adventure&amp;rsquo;s placement rules, then optionally use the action. Actions include robots for building connections, water/plants for resources, energy for boosting effects, astronauts for modifying numbers (-2 to +2), and planning for strategic crosses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brilliance is in the tension: which number-action combo serves your immediate needs versus long-term strategy? Do you grab the perfect number but weak action, or the action you desperately need with an awkward number? Every choice matters because you&amp;rsquo;re racing toward three objectives while avoiding system errors that could end your game prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The game continues until someone completes all 3 objectives, fills every space on their sheet, or crosses all system errors. These conditions apply to both solo and multiplayer modes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;adventure-variety&#34;&gt;Adventure Variety&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed through Adventures 1-4 is a steady increase in difficulty and the introduction of new mechanics. The theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t change but evolves beautifully, starting from ship preparation (Adventure 1), progressing through the journey to the moon, arrival, and beginning mining operations (Adventure 4).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, Adventure 4 introduces mining as a two-step process: first entering numbers, then extracting resources by completing columns. Each adventure builds on the previous one while adding its own twist, creating a cohesive narrative of lunar colonization. The 8 adventures together form a complete story of establishing humanity&amp;rsquo;s presence on the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;campaign-mode&#34;&gt;Campaign Mode&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The campaign mode is where Welcome to the Moon truly shines. You score points at each scenario based on whether you accomplished objectives. You track your progress on a sheet included at the end of the campaign book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished the campaign yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing that satisfying feeling of having more points than the automa. However, each new scenario is more complicated and offers more points for completion, so the challenge intensifies. There are branching scenarios, in the first campaign part, these determine which 3 missions appear in each adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The full campaign requires at least 16 plays (8 adventures × 2 campaign parts). It&amp;rsquo;s easily replayed and simple to reset, making it perfect for multiple campaign runs or teaching new players.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/setup-adventure-3.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Setup for Adventure 3&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Setup for Adventure 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;solo-mode&#34;&gt;Solo Mode&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In solo play, you draw 3 cards from a single deck each round. Select 2 cards, one for the number, one for the action, and give the remaining card to the automa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At game end, the automa scores by summing cards of each type and multiplying by a level-specific multiplier. When mission cards are drawn, you follow AI-specific actions (usually crossing bonuses from your board to simulate multiplayer competition).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When all cards are drawn, reshuffle the discard pile (excluding automa cards). Mission cards are shuffled into the entire deck for subsequent draws.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/automa.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Automa cards&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Automa Cards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-curve&#34;&gt;Learning Curve&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules are simple, straightforward, and require no constant rulebook reference, everything flows smoothly. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taught it to anyone yet, but I estimate 5-10 minutes would be sufficient to explain the core concepts. Each adventure&amp;rsquo;s unique rules are clearly explained and easy to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparison-to-other-flip-and-writes&#34;&gt;Comparison to Other Flip-and-Writes&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t played the original Welcome To…, so I can&amp;rsquo;t compare directly. However, when comparing with other flip-and-writes like &lt;strong&gt;Demeter&lt;/strong&gt;, Welcome to the Moon stands out as more complete due to its story dimension. The campaign structure and narrative progression elevate it beyond typical flip &amp;amp; write experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing through the campaign and just finished mission 4, mission 5 is next. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet started the second campaign part with the hidden narrative cards, as I&amp;rsquo;m still working through the learning portion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost only once to the AI and won 3 times. It&amp;rsquo;s been a real pleasure moving through the different adventures and reading the story. The adventures have a logical progression that makes thematic sense and keeps me eager for the next challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 2&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Adventure 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-4.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 4&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Adventure 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros-and-cons&#34;&gt;Pros and Cons&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Love:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excellent variability and replayability through 8 distinct adventures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Campaign mode adds meaningful narrative progression&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reusable sheets are environmentally friendly and space-efficient&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simple rules that flow smoothly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Satisfying strategic tension in every card choice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Great organization inside the box&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quick playtime (25-30 minutes) perfect for multiple sessions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Holds It Back:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While excellent, I suspect replayability will diminish after completing the campaign&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flip &amp;amp; write mechanics, while well-executed here, aren&amp;rsquo;t my absolute favorite genre&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The game creates that &amp;ldquo;one more play&amp;rdquo; urge during the campaign, but I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain about long-term replay value once the story is complete&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 9 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon successfully captures the excitement of lunar colonization in an accessible flip &amp;amp; write format. The 8 adventures provide significant variety, the campaign mode adds compelling narrative depth, and the reusable sheets are an excellent design choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is probably one of my favorite flip-and-writes. It&amp;rsquo;s quick to play, easy to set up, and the campaign structure gives it staying power that most flip-and-writes lack. The steady difficulty progression and introduction of new mechanics keep each adventure fresh and challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy flip-and-writes and want one with excellent replayability, a compelling campaign, and meaningful strategic decisions, Welcome to the Moon is highly recommended. Even if flip-and-writes aren&amp;rsquo;t typically your favorite, the narrative structure and adventure variety make this worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Welcome to the Moon? Which adventure is your favorite? How far have you gotten in the campaign? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your experiences!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/339789/welcome-to-the-moon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Board Game Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bluecocker.com/en/landing-page/#post-987&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Blue Cocker Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/yvB3RR7xxwQ?si=YIaDCTnuaXu1dqSX&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Solooperative Games&lt;/a&gt; - Solo playthrough of the Adventure 1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>My 2025 Board Gaming Year in Review</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post My 2025 Board Gaming Year in Review&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;re all doing well and have started enjoying a few plays for this start of the year. I&amp;rsquo;m here today to review my 2025 through the games I played.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My 2025 in Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;136 plays (118 solo)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;45 new-to-me games, mostly from my own collection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Around 128 hours of gameplay&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/general-stats.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;2025 Game Stats&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;2025 Game Stats&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a good year for board gaming. I had some moments when I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to play, but on other occasions I played a lot. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d say it was well-balanced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My passion for playing, but even more for sharing my enthusiasm, encouraged me to finally start this blog. This is a great achievement and a good way to put into words my feelings about the games I&amp;rsquo;ve played.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Top 5 Games of 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anachrony&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trickerion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Galactic Cruise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obsession&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Underwater Cities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;games-that-defined-my-year&#34;&gt;Games That Defined My Year&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anachrony&lt;/strong&gt; – My #1 game of 2025. A time-travel themed worker placement game where you send resources back from the future to help your past self prepare for an impending apocalypse. The brilliance lies in managing temporal paradoxes while building your civilization and preparing for impact. The theme is deeply integrated into every mechanism, borrowing from your future self creates debt you must repay, and the asymmetric Path powers make each playthrough feel unique. The collector&amp;rsquo;s editions with the exosuit miniatures is stunning, and the strategic depth keeps me coming back. It&amp;rsquo;s complex, yes, but the theme makes every rule make sense. This is peak Mindclash design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/anachrony.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Anachrony&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Anachrony&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trickerion&lt;/strong&gt; – My #2 game of 2025. A worker placement game about rival stage magicians competing to become the city&amp;rsquo;s greatest illusionist. What sets this apart is how thematically rich it is, you&amp;rsquo;re not just placing workers, you&amp;rsquo;re preparing elaborate tricks, managing your theater, gathering components, and performing spectacular illusions. The darkness of the setting (set in a fictional late 19th-century city with occult undertones) gives it atmosphere that few worker placement games achieve. Learning your first trick and successfully performing it feels genuinely rewarding. It&amp;rsquo;s heavy, demanding careful planning across multiple rounds, but every action feels meaningful and thematic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/trickerion.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Trickerion&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Trickerion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galactic Cruise&lt;/strong&gt; – I backed this game because I loved the graphics, story, and mechanics, and it became my #3 game of the year. Designed by T.K. King, Dennis Northcott, and Koltin Thompson, illustrated by Ian O&amp;rsquo;Toole, and published by Kingson Key Games as their first game. I heard someone say after its release, &amp;ldquo;It should be prohibited to have such a good game as your first.&amp;rdquo; I completely agree. You&amp;rsquo;re managing a luxury space cruise ship, balancing passenger satisfaction, ship upgrades, and navigation through a beautifully illustrated galaxy. The game is simply perfect, fun, gorgeously illustrated (you&amp;rsquo;ll feel a Vital Lacerda vibe since Ian O&amp;rsquo;Toole frequently works with Vital), and the mechanics are logical and intuitive. Every decision matters, but it never feels overwhelming. My discovery of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/galactic-cruise-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Galactic Cruise&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Galactic Cruise&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/galactic-cruise.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Galactic Cruise&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Galactic Cruise&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/&#34; &gt;Obsession&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – My #4 game of 2025. An elegant hand management game set in Victorian England where you manage a fallen aristocratic family trying to improve their social standing through marriage. The servant rotation system creates interesting tactical decisions, and reputation management is crucial, you must carefully balance building your reputation with acquiring the cards and improvements you need. The courtship mechanic, where you compete to impress the Fairchild orphans, adds wonderful narrative tension. Each of the four families plays distinctly different due to their unique starting advantages. The Downton Abbey aesthetic is beautiful, and solo games run smoothly in about 45 minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s thematic without being heavy, strategic without being punishing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/obsession-servants.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Obsession&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Obsession&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/&#34; &gt;Underwater Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – My #5 game of 2025. A card-driven worker placement game about building underwater civilizations. I took too long to try this, but once I did, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d been missing out on tremendous fun. The genius is in the color-matching system, matching card colors to action spaces unlocks powerful effects, creating a satisfying puzzle every turn. It&amp;rsquo;s simple to understand yet complex in execution, with many strategic paths to explore. The game is tight, you&amp;rsquo;re constantly working with limited resources, carefully considering each move. I improved from 72 points in my first play to 83 in my second, showing the rewarding learning curve. The asymmetric player boards and variable card draws mean every game feels different. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating in the best way possible, I immediately wanted to play again after each loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/play.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Underwater Cities&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;other-mindclash-games-i-loved&#34;&gt;Other Mindclash Games I Loved&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cerebria&lt;/strong&gt; – An abstract area control game about the struggle between Bliss and Gloom inside a human mind. The theme is unusual and brilliantly executed, you&amp;rsquo;re literally fighting for control of someone&amp;rsquo;s emotions and thoughts. Visually stunning and mechanically tight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perseverance: Episode 1&lt;/strong&gt; – A dice placement and area majority game where you defend your camp against dinosaur attacks. The solo mode with two AI &amp;ldquo;Dissidents&amp;rdquo; creates a challenging puzzle where you must carefully calculate dice placements to maximize efficiency while anticipating opponent moves. Strategic and tense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All Mindclash games share common DNA: they&amp;rsquo;re typically heavy with substantial rules, but the themes are so present that mechanisms make intuitive sense. Set aside at least 3 hours for setup and gameplay, embrace the complexity, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be rewarded with deeply satisfying experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/cerebria.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Cerebria&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Cerebria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/perseverance.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Perseverance: Episode 1&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Perseverance: Episode 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;solo-gaming-gems&#34;&gt;Solo Gaming Gems&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robinson Crusoe&lt;/strong&gt; – One of the best solo board games of all time, and perhaps the most brutal. If you struggle with losing and get easily frustrated, stay away, this game is merciless. It&amp;rsquo;s a survival game with scenario-based gameplay where everything that can go wrong will go wrong. The base game includes 7 scenarios with increasing difficulty, and the Book of Adventures expansion adds many more organized by difficulty and theme. Despite the punishing difficulty, or perhaps because of it, every small victory feels earned. The game creates emergent stories through your desperate decisions. I&amp;rsquo;ve played many hours over the years and I&amp;rsquo;m still in love with its cruel brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/robinson-crusoe.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Robinson Crusoe&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Robinson Crusoe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oniverse Games (Onirim/Nautilion/Sylvion)&lt;/strong&gt; – I played three games from the Oniverse world this year. My favorite is &lt;strong&gt;Nautilion&lt;/strong&gt;, closely followed by &lt;strong&gt;Onirim&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Nautilion&lt;/strong&gt;, you race to reach the Lighthouse in the Oceanic Depths before the Phantom Submarine reaches your homeland, the Happy Isles. You roll three dice each turn and choose which to use to advance your submarine, advance the Phantom. Your submarine needs a full crew of different specialists, and the placement rules (filling positions adjacent to your starting cabin) add satisfying spatial puzzle elements. The game includes several different submarines and expansions for variety. It&amp;rsquo;s tense, quick (20-30 minutes), and perfect when you want meaningful decisions in a short timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All &lt;strong&gt;Oniverse&lt;/strong&gt; games share a dreamy aesthetic and are designed specifically for solo play (though they support two players). I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested multiplayer because they&amp;rsquo;re simply perfect as solo experiences, compact, quick, and deeply satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/onirim.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Onirim&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Onirim&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/nautilion-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Nautilion&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Nautilion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy of Yu&lt;/strong&gt; – A solo campaign game that&amp;rsquo;s story-driven with a clever deck-building mechanism. You play through the story of Yu the Great, the legendary Chinese emperor who controlled the floods. The campaign evolves as you make decisions, and the deck-building creates a satisfying sense of progression. Each scenario builds on the last, and your choices have consequences that ripple through the campaign. Engaging storytelling combined with solid mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/&#34; &gt;R.A.V.E.L.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – A compact dice puzzle game perfect for short sessions or travel. You manipulate dice on a grid to solve Cog cards with specific requirements. It&amp;rsquo;s pure puzzle satisfaction in a tiny package, 10 minutes of clever spatial reasoning and resource management. The adjustable difficulty means it scales from casual to genuinely challenging. One of my favorite &amp;ldquo;lunch break&amp;rdquo; games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/legacy-of-yu.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Legacy of Yu&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Legacy of Yu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/view.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;R.A.V.E.L.&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenging-strategy-games&#34;&gt;Challenging Strategy Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endeavor: Deep Sea&lt;/strong&gt; – Lead a submarine on missions to develop sustainable ocean projects and preserve marine life. This surprised me as one of my favorite discoveries of the year. It&amp;rsquo;s fresh, thematic, and hard to win, exactly how I like my games. You must carefully balance research, exploration, and conservation, calculating several moves ahead. Do you research new technologies or investigate your surroundings? Deploy your submarine or focus on base upgrades? Every decision matters. For puzzle lovers who enjoy 2-hour strategic journeys with a strong environmental theme, this is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/endeavor.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Endeavor: Deep Sea&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Endeavor: Deep Sea&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civolution&lt;/strong&gt; – A civilization development game with complete player control wrapped in an unusual sci-fi premise. You&amp;rsquo;re a student in the far future taking your &amp;ldquo;Civolution exam&amp;rdquo; by simulating the rise of a civilization on a giant console. You gather resources, migrate populations, and guide your people through ages of development. Trait cards provide special benefits, gills for underwater adaptation, claws for hunting, various evolutionary advantages. What could feel dry (civilization building, resource management) becomes captivating through clever framing and intuitive mechanics. It&amp;rsquo;s challenging to beat but deeply satisfying when your civilization thrives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/civolution.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Civolution&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Civolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great Western Trail&lt;/strong&gt; – A rancher game about the cattle drive from Texas to Kansas City. You collect cow cards while navigating a hazardous trail filled with obstacles and opportunities. The deck-building combined with the trail movement creates interesting decisions, do you improve your herd, build structures along the trail, or hire specialists? The learning curve is accessible, and the game reveals its depth gradually. It&amp;rsquo;s become a modern classic for good reason, every playthrough tells a different story of your cattle empire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/great-western-trail.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Great Western Trail&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Great Western Trail&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;classic-euro-games&#34;&gt;Classic Euro Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viticulture&lt;/strong&gt; – It took me time to try this because I thought wine-making wouldn&amp;rsquo;t interest me. How wrong I was! This is worker placement done beautifully, thematic and streamlined. You plant vines, harvest grapes, age wine, and fulfill orders across the seasons. The visitor cards add variability and help smooth out bad draws. It&amp;rsquo;s accessible enough for newer gamers but has enough depth for experienced players. Now I understand why it&amp;rsquo;s considered a modern classic, and I&amp;rsquo;m eager to try the Tuscany expansion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/viticulture.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Viticulture&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Viticulture&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;relaxing--beautiful-games&#34;&gt;Relaxing &amp;amp; Beautiful Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meadow&lt;/strong&gt; – A peaceful tableau-building game where you create the most beautiful meadow environment with various animals, plants, and landscapes. The artwork is gorgeous, watercolor illustrations that evoke nature walks and quiet observation. It&amp;rsquo;s competitive but gentle, perfect for unwinding after heavier games. The card combinations create satisfying moments of discovery, like assembling a nature journal page by page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdant&lt;/strong&gt; – A game about houseplant care that&amp;rsquo;s more engaging than it sounds. You arrange plants and furniture to create the most aesthetically pleasing and thriving indoor garden. The spatial puzzle of plant placement, considering light requirements, pot matching, and room aesthetics, is genuinely satisfying. Quick to play (30-45 minutes), relaxing in theme, but with enough decisions to stay interesting. Perfect for a calm evening of gaming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/meadow.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Meadow&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Meadow&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/verdant.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Verdant&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Verdant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;creature-collection-games&#34;&gt;Creature Collection Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dragon Eclipse&lt;/strong&gt; – A narrative game from Awaken Realms with a Pokémon-style collection vibe. The story is engaging, and the artwork is absolutely beautiful, each Mystling feels unique and characterful. However, I must highlight a significant weakness: the gameplay becomes repetitive. Despite loving the illustrations and narrative premise, the repetitive nature of encounters and actions started to feel tedious. It&amp;rsquo;s a game I want to love more than I actually do, the presentation promises more variety than the mechanics deliver for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wondrous Creatures&lt;/strong&gt; – A 2025 release that achieved well-deserved success. Like Dragon Eclipse, it features creature collection with Pokémon-style appeal, but without the scenario structure, this is pure collection and tableau building. The illustrations are stunning, and the gameplay stays fresh through variable card effects and strategic depth. Each creature feels special, and building your collection is consistently satisfying. For anyone who loves beautiful creatures and light-to-medium strategy, this is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/dragon-eclispe.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Dragon Eclipse&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Dragon Eclipse&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/wondrous-creatures.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Wondrous Creatures&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Wondrous Creatures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;looking-ahead-to-2026&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead to 2026&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;For 2026, I&amp;rsquo;m taking on the &lt;strong&gt;Alphabet Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; that consists in playing at least one game for each letter of the alphabet. I hope to discover some lesser-known games and find new favorites along the way. I play for fun, so I enjoy both simple games and heavy board games equally. The journey matters more than the complexity!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited to explore games that don&amp;rsquo;t get as much attention in the mainstream board gaming community. If you have recommendations for hidden gems, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear them!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What were your standout games from 2025? Are you taking on any gaming challenges this year? Let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>December 2025 Plays</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post December 2025 Plays&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wish you all a great new year and all the best for 2026!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my plays from the last month of the year. December was a good gaming month with 17 plays across 8 different games. Half of them were new to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/decembers-game.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;December&amp;#39;s Stats&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;December&amp;rsquo;s Stats&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;game-of-the-month-obsession&#34;&gt;Game of the Month: Obsession&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Victorian hand management game completely won me over and earned my highest rating of the month at &lt;strong&gt;9/10&lt;/strong&gt;. Managing a fallen aristocratic family while competing to impress the Fairchild orphans through hosting social events creates a compelling narrative arc. The servant rotation system, reputation management, and courtship mechanics all work together beautifully. Each of the four families plays distinctly different due to their unique starting advantages, adding tremendous replayability. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/&#34; &gt;Read my full Obsession review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/obsession-material.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Obsession&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Obsession&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-top-games-this-month&#34;&gt;My Top Games This Month&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underwater Cities (8.5/10)&lt;/strong&gt; impressed me with its tight, strategic gameplay where each move must be carefully considered. The card-driven action selection creates a satisfying puzzle: matching card colors to action spaces unlocks powerful effects, but you&amp;rsquo;re constantly working with limited resources. I improved from 72 points in my first play to 83 in my second, showing the rewarding learning curve. What makes this game special is the frustration in the best way possible, I immediately wanted to play again after each loss. The asymmetric player boards and variable card draws mean every game feels fresh, and the combos can be incredibly satisfying when everything clicks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/player-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities player board&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Player Board&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;strong&gt;Obsession and Underwater Cities&lt;/strong&gt; feature hand management with puzzle elements that kept me coming back for &amp;ldquo;just one more game.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-biggest-surprise&#34;&gt;The Biggest Surprise&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracks: Siren Bay (7/10)&lt;/strong&gt; surprised me most with its unique gameplay. Discovering what happened and helping to solve a case using only sounds is challenging but really satisfying. It&amp;rsquo;s completely different from typical detective games and offers an innovative mechanic I hadn&amp;rsquo;t experienced before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/example.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Tracks: Siren Bay&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Tracks: Siren Bay&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;other-games-played&#34;&gt;Other Games Played&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endless Winter (8.5/10)&lt;/strong&gt; made a return this month, a game I enjoyed a lot last month. On this second play, I tested the mini-expansions Ceremonial Grounds and Canine Familiars. Ceremonial Grounds adds a new mechanic at the end of eclipse phases: you can select one of the rituals that gives you immediate points based on criteria like food and materials you have. Once selected, you can no longer bury cards, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great point boost. As for Canine Familiars, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use the cards during the play, probably I missed how it could improve the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/endless-winter-player-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Endless Winter player board&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Endless Winter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troyes Dice (8/10)&lt;/strong&gt; is a Roll &amp;amp; Write that continued to challenge me. The transparent dice mechanic and medieval city-building theme create satisfying strategic depth, and I&amp;rsquo;m still improving my scores with each play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/end-game.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Troyes Dice end game&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R.A.V.E.L. (8/10)&lt;/strong&gt; is a quick logic puzzle where you solve enigmas by moving dice to meet specific card conditions. Perfect for filling short gaming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/view.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;R.A.V.E.L.&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.A.R.I.&lt;/strong&gt; has you guide a robot on Mars through a series of enigmas based on movement mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/game-mari.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;M.A.R.I.&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;M.A.R.I.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SmartGames: IQ Six Pro&lt;/strong&gt; reminded me why puzzle games are perfect travel companions. It&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasure to come back to these clever, portable challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260103-december-plays/iq6pro.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;SmartGames: IQ Six Pro&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;IQ Six Pro&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-2026&#34;&gt;Looking Forward to 2026&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to continue exploring these games in the new year. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly looking forward to testing &lt;strong&gt;Tapestry&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Wayfarers of the South Tigris&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-about-you&#34;&gt;What About You?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;What were your favorite games from December? Did any of you try Obsession or Underwater Cities? Any new discoveries that surprised you? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Obsession: A Victorian Hand Management Game</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Obsession: A Victorian Hand Management Game&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to bring you Obsession today!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obsession is an elegant hand management game set in Victorian England. You&amp;rsquo;ll manage a fallen aristocratic family, host social events, and compete for advantageous marriages. The theme is beautifully integrated, and the gameplay is smooth and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obsession is a 2018 release for 1-4 players, ages 14+, with a playtime of 30-90 minutes. It was designed and illustrated by Dan Hallagan and published by Kayenta Games. The Spanish version is published by Maldito Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Obsession box&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Obsession box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Obsession, you are the head of a fallen family in Derbyshire, England. Your family experienced hard times in the late 18th century and is now hoping to improve its status in the mid-19th century. One way to improve your standing is through marriage, and it happens that two orphans from the wealthy Fairchild family are of marriageable age in Derbyshire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the head of your family, you&amp;rsquo;ll improve your estate, organize social events, invite aristocrats as guests, and hire servants to enhance your reputation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To win, you need the most victory points. Points are earned from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Country estate improvement tiles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guest cards&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Victory point cards gained during the game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reputation (converted to points using a table in the rulebook)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Objective cards&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Servants (2 points each)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Money&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;components&#34;&gt;Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game includes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A main board where activities are displayed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A board with the turn tracker&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personal boards (one for each of the 4 families in the base game)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Player materials&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meeples in several colors representing servants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cards: guest cards (levels 1 and 2), victory point cards, theme cards, and objective cards&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Country estate improvement tiles stored in a bag.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-material.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Obsession game boards&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Obsession game boards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-four-families&#34;&gt;The Four Families&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each family provides a unique starting advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cavendish starts with a reputation token on level 4 of the reputation wheel (closer to reaching reputation 2) while other families start on level 1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asquith starts with one extra card, an additional family member&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ponsonby starts with £300&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;York starts with an extra footman servant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set up the two boards. On the board with the round tracker, place the round marker on the first space and shuffle the victory point and theme cards onto their designated spots.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the main board, place the guest cards and objective cards. Put all tiles except monuments into the bag. Select the number of monuments indicated in the rulebook based on player count, then add them to the bag. Draw 6 tiles from the bag to create the tile river. Only tiles of levels 1-3 and specific services listed in the rulebook are accepted for setup — return any others to the bag. Sort the tiles in ascending order on the board and stack duplicate tiles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prepare each player board by placing the reputation level token on &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; at the center of the reputation wheel, then place your reputation tracking token on level 1 of the wheel (or level 4 for Cavendish). Add the 5 starting servants to your available services. Shuffle the starting casual guests and distribute 2 to each player to add to their 4 family cards (or 5 for Asquith).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-setup-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Setup for one player&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Setup for one player&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-reputation-system&#34;&gt;The Reputation System&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your player board features a reputation wheel with 5 levels around it and a reputation level tracker in the center. As you gain reputation during the game, you advance your token around the wheel. When you complete the 5th level of the wheel, you increase your reputation level by 1 point (moving the center token from 1 to 2, for example) and your tracking token returns to level 1 of the wheel to begin the cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-servants.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Reputation wheel and available servants&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Reputation wheel and available servants&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game spans 16-20 turns depending on whether you&amp;rsquo;re playing normal or extended gameplay. In solo mode, games typically last around 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;On your turn, select a country estate improvement tile from your estate to host an event. Choose exactly the number of guests indicated on the tile from your hand and assign the required servants to the event. While you cannot choose which guest cards you acquire (they come from the common pool), you do have control over which country estate improvement tiles you purchase — this strategic tile selection is key to building your engine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can only use servants that are currently available. After performing an event, servants move to &amp;ldquo;used services.&amp;rdquo; At the start of your next turn, servants rotate from &amp;ldquo;used&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;servants&amp;rsquo; quarters&amp;rdquo; and from &amp;ldquo;servants&amp;rsquo; quarters&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;available services.&amp;rdquo; Only available servants can be assigned to events.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Events and guests provide bonuses or penalties related to reputation, acquiring new guests, money, or servants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After resolving effects, if this is the first time you&amp;rsquo;re using this improvement tile, flip it to its other side. The tile now shows different points, requirements, and effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You then have the option to purchase a new tile. You can only acquire one tile per turn. The cost is shown on the board and may be modified by tile effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-five-improvement-types&#34;&gt;The Five Improvement Types&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Country estate improvements come in 5 types:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Essentials: basic improvements for your estate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Services: usually don&amp;rsquo;t host events but provide benefits for servants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Estate: core estate buildings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prestige: high-status improvements&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sporting: outdoor and recreational facilities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/onsession-play-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Country estate improvements at the end of the game&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Country estate improvements at the end of the game&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-importance-of-reputation&#34;&gt;The Importance of Reputation&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reputation is crucial in Obsession. You cannot play guest cards or country estate improvements if your reputation level is lower than the requirement shown on the card or tile. Higher reputation unlocks better guests and improvements with superior benefits. Managing your reputation carefully is key to success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;special-events&#34;&gt;Special Events&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Certain turns trigger special events as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Village Fair: if you&amp;rsquo;ve flipped the Study tile, gain £300 and 3 reputation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Opportunities: gain additional objectives (you must discard one objective at each courtship event), host events and invite guests above your reputation level, or build additional buildings this turn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;courtship-events&#34;&gt;Courtship Events&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the game, there are 4 courtship event phases. On these turns, you don&amp;rsquo;t play a tile but instead resolve a thematic event. The Fairchild orphans attend your events during these phases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A card is revealed showing the theme for that phase, corresponding to one of the 5 improvement types. You count the points from tiles of that specific type in your estate. The player with the highest points gains one of the Fairchild cards to play this turn plus a victory point card. In case of a tie, the Fairchilds don&amp;rsquo;t join any family, but tied players each take a victory point card.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the final courtship event, instead of counting points from only one improvement type, you count points from all themes revealed throughout the game. If a theme appears twice, count its points twice. The player with the most points gains a Fairchild card worth 8 VP plus a victory point card.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-boards.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Courtship events. In this example 2 Essentials, 1 Sporting and 1 Prestige&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Courtship events. In this example 2 Essentials, 1 Sporting and 1 Prestige&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-of-the-game&#34;&gt;End of the Game&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When all turns have been played, count your points to determine the winner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;component-quality&#34;&gt;Component Quality&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate the material quality in this game. The cards and tokens are excellent quality. Inside the box, you&amp;rsquo;ll find dividers organizing the material, one section for each family with their respective cards and materials, plus two sections for remaining components. The bag provided for tiles is large and high quality. The illustrations give a Downton Abbey vibe that&amp;rsquo;s very pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-bag.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Big bag to shuffle the tiles&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Big bag to shuffle the tiles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;solo-mode&#34;&gt;Solo Mode&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solo mode features an automa opponent you must beat. There are 3 difficulty levels, each with 3 sub-levels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solo mode is simple to manage, using only 2 cards and a 20-sided die:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One card shows the automa&amp;rsquo;s score and victory points by color to consider in each courtship event phase&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another card indicates which tile to remove from the market based on the die roll, with different tables for turns with and without monuments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-automa.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Solo automa material&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Solo automa material&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played 3 times, testing three different families: first Cavendish, then Ponsonby, and finally York. I used the easiest solo mode for all three games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I won my first 2 plays at the basic level and thought it was easy. But as soon as I tested the second difficulty level, it became much harder, and I understood the full beauty of the game. Each family plays quite differently — starting closer to reputation 2 (Cavendish) versus extra money (Ponsonby) versus an extra servant (York) creates distinctly different strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-rating&#34;&gt;My Rating&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 9 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gameplay is fantastic, quick, easy to prepare, and really enjoyable. Solo games take around 45 minutes, which is perfect. The theme is present but not overwhelming, which is good for players who aren&amp;rsquo;t enthusiastic about Victorian themes. The solo mode is enjoyable and not easy to beat, with scalable difficulty that keeps you coming back. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably return to this game often and possibly purchase the expansions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251227-obsession/obsession-end-of-game.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of game&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;End of game&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obsession beautifully integrates hand management with servant management in a thematic Victorian setting. While guest acquisition is somewhat random, you have full control over which country estate improvements you add to your estate, allowing you to build toward specific strategies. The courtship mechanics add tension and strategic depth, while the servant rotation system creates interesting tactical decisions. Reputation management is crucial — you must carefully balance building your reputation with acquiring the cards and improvements you need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Component quality is excellent, and the solo mode provides a solid challenge with scalable difficulty. The four families offer meaningful variety in starting positions and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy thematic games with elegant mechanics, hand management, and appreciate Victorian-era settings (or at least don&amp;rsquo;t mind them), Obsession is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn-1&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Obsession? Which family did you play? How did your courtship events go? Have you tried the expansions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/231733/obsession/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Board Game Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kayenta-games.myshopify.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Kayenta Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.malditogames.com/juegos/obsesion-juego/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Maldito Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/F1ubiA2qZOI?si=-WRf3QgzYm9xB0-f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Unna – Obsession playthrough – Spanish reviewer with a fantastic playthrough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/6Gjs_UjUHDY?si=VG9urXsYchUi9riK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;One Stop Coop Shop – Great solo playthrough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Troyes Dice: A Medieval Roll &amp; Write</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Troyes Dice: A Medieval Roll &amp; Write&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time I&amp;rsquo;m bringing you a Roll &amp;amp; Write game: Troyes Dice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice is a strategic dice drafting and city-building game where you compete to leave your mark on a medieval city. Despite a steep learning curve, it offers satisfying depth and good replayability through variable dice results and an optional expansion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice is a 2020 release for 1-10 players, ages 12+, with a playtime of 20-30 minutes. It was designed by Sébastien Dujardin, Xavier Georges, and Alain Orban, illustrated by Alexandre Roche, and published by Pearl Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/box-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Troyes Dice box&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Troyes Dice, you represent a wealthy Champagne family working alongside the nobles, civilians, and clergy to improve the city and leave your mark on its history during the Middle Ages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each social order has its responsibility: nobles protect the land and ensure justice, civilians provide the hard work necessary to supply food and goods essential to city life, and clergy ensure spiritual awakening and cultural development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You score points by constructing fortresses to protect the city, cathedrals to improve culture, and markets for commerce. You&amp;rsquo;ll also participate in constructing prestigious buildings linked to each social order. Through construction, you&amp;rsquo;ll gain knowledge, money, and influence, which will bring more people to your city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your final score combines points from constructions, resources, and the population of your city. The player with the highest score wins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solo mode works as a Beat Your Own Score (BYOS), where you try to improve with each game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/material-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Troyes Dice components&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice components&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To set up the game, place the game board at the center of the table and turn the wheel&amp;rsquo;s small layer to show day 1. Place the 9 Plaza tiles randomly around the board, flipped to a random side. Select one player to be the dice master. Each player takes a scoresheet and pencil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For your first play, number each district 1 to 6 from left to right. In future plays, you can determine the first number by rolling a die.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/setup-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Setup for one player&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Setup for one player&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game consists of 16 rounds, 8 day phases and 8 night phases. Each round represents one phase and is split between morning and night. The day/night wheel simply tracks these 16 rounds. During each phase, the dice master shakes the dice and places them on the Plazas in ascending order. Day plazas are on the white side of the board wheel, and night plazas are on the black side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s a tie between the black die and another die, the black die comes first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dice master role remains the same player throughout the game according to the rulebook, though gaming groups can decide to rotate if they prefer, but won&amp;rsquo;t impact gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-black-die--attacks-and-destruction&#34;&gt;The Black Die – Attacks and Destruction&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The black die represents attacks on the Plaza where it&amp;rsquo;s placed, making that Plaza unavailable. From day 3 onward, the black die also destroys the Plaza. When a Plaza is destroyed, you must cross out all related buildings (not yet used) that match both the die number (district) and the Plaza color on your scoresheet. The Plaza is then flipped to its other side for the next round, changing its color. Note that 3 Plazas have the same color on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/wheel-and-destroyed-plaza.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Black die effect on the wheel and a destroyed Plaza&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Black die effect&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;scoresheet&#34;&gt;Scoresheet&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scoresheet is divided into 3 districts related to nobles, civilians, and clergy, each composed of 2 different buildings: nobles construct fortresses and gain influence (this protects buildings from the die number associated with that district), civilians create markets that allow you to gather money, and clergy build cathedrals that bring knowledge (each cathedral is linked to a building, and construction allows those buildings to score at game&amp;rsquo;s end).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the scoresheet is the Civil track. When constructing buildings, you bring people to your city. Each citizen gives you 1 point at the end of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/scoresheet-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Scoresheet example showing the building tracks and resources&#34; width=&#34;550&amp;#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Scoresheet example showing the building tracks and resources. Image credit: Pearl Games rulebook&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;selecting-and-constructing&#34;&gt;Selecting and Constructing&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the dice are placed each round, you select one Plaza with a transparent (colored) die. The transparent die&amp;rsquo;s color matches the Plaza color. Depending on which Plaza you select, there&amp;rsquo;s a cost to pay. You can manipulate the color or number of the die by spending knowledge or influence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;component-quality&#34;&gt;Component Quality&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scoresheets have good paper quality, but there&amp;rsquo;s one drawback: they&amp;rsquo;re only printed on one side, which feels wasteful. The dice are big and satisfying to shake, but the numbers on the transparent dice are painted rather than engraved. This could lead to the numbers wearing off over time with repeated use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;replayability&#34;&gt;Replayability&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game has good replayability since the dice never follow the same pattern, requiring constant adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;expansion&#34;&gt;Expansion&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game includes a small expansion in the box called Banquets and Raiders that attaches effects to Plazas with the same color on both sides. These effects are positive until the Plaza is destroyed for the first time. After destruction, the effect becomes negative for the rest of the game, but you can still select dice from those Plazas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/end-game-with-expansion.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Expansion end game example&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Expansion end game example&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-combo-example&#34;&gt;A Combo Example&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When playing with the expansion, I used a die from a Plaza that allowed me to gain one influence, one coin, and one knowledge by constructing a specific building type. By doing so, I activated a bonus on one of the tracks that provided me with one more civilian. That civilian completed a bonus on the civil track, which allowed me to construct another building. These cascading effects are incredibly satisfying!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game also includes challenges where you face the game creators by comparing scores. Each challenge has specific instructions provided.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played 4 times so far, and my scores have been 50, 46, 56, and 64. The progression shows the learning curve in action, after an initial dip, I&amp;rsquo;ve been steadily improving as I understand the strategies better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategy-tips-for-beginners&#34;&gt;Strategy Tips for Beginners&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My advice: start by constructing fortresses whenever possible. They&amp;rsquo;ll help protect your districts after round 3, preventing destruction from the black die. Also, make good use of dice modifiers (knowledge and influence) to create combos, they&amp;rsquo;re key to higher scores.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparison-with-other-roll--writes&#34;&gt;Comparison with Other Roll &amp;amp; Writes&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played several Roll &amp;amp; Write games like Trek 12 and Penny Papers. Troyes Dice has a completely different mechanic with its transparent dice and board game integration. I preferred Troyes Dice over Penny Papers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When compared with Trek 12, the sensations are similar even though the mechanics are different. Troyes Dice focuses on plaza dice placement, while Trek 12 emphasizes mathematical thinking to scale the mountain. Both offer satisfying strategic depth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;player-count&#34;&gt;Player Count&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve only played solo so far, so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on multiplayer experience. However, based on the mechanics, the game has no player interaction, so the feeling should be similar at any player count. The main difference in multiplayer would be the challenge of competing for the best score.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;language-dependency&#34;&gt;Language Dependency&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game has no language dependency. There&amp;rsquo;s no text on the components, only the rulebook requires translation. The rules are available on the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website, making it accessible to players of any language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-rating&#34;&gt;My Rating&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 8 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really good Roll &amp;amp; Write with a solid learning curve. At the beginning, I was completely lost, not knowing which dice to select or what to do. After my fourth play, I have strategies and feel much more confident. My improving scores show the rewarding progression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tested the expansion and enjoyed it a lot. The cascading combos make the game even more satisfying. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested the challenges yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251223-troyes-dice/end-game.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End game example&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;End game example&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Troyes Dice is a satisfying Roll &amp;amp; Write that rewards strategic thinking and planning. While the first game can feel overwhelming, the learning curve is rewarding, and each game feels different thanks to dice variability. The expansion adds even more depth without adding much complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The component quality has some minor issues (single-sided scoresheets, painted dice numbers), but these don&amp;rsquo;t significantly impact the gameplay experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy Roll &amp;amp; Write games with meaningful decisions and don&amp;rsquo;t mind a bit of initial confusion, Troyes Dice is definitely worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Troyes Dice? How many plays did it take you to feel comfortable with the strategy? Have you tried the expansion? What&amp;rsquo;s your highest score?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/284584/troyes-dice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Board Game Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pearlgames.be/boardgame/troyes-dice/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Pearl Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/WsN1L2gYeEs?si=3IPcWaIJGJO_KyQf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Before You Play – Playthrough and Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>R.A.V.E.L.: Quick, Clever, and Addictive</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post R.A.V.E.L.: Quick, Clever, and Addictive&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m bringing you a little solo board game gem: R.A.V.E.L.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. is a quick, clever dice manipulation puzzle that&amp;rsquo;s perfect for filling a short gaming session. Despite its small size and simple rules, it offers surprising depth and replayability through adjustable difficulty levels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. is a 2025 release for 1 player, ages 10+, with a playtime of approximately 10 minutes. The game was designed by Daniel McKinley, illustrated by Christine Alcouffe, and published by inPatience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/box-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;R.A.V.E.L. box&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. box&#xA;          &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/413248/ravel&#34;&gt;via BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-ravel-stand-for&#34;&gt;What Does R.A.V.E.L. Stand For?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. stands for Rare Artefact Vertiginous Enigmatic Logical, an endless resettable puzzle where you manipulate 8 dice of 3 different colors on a grid to solve Cog cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The setup is really quick, making this game perfect for a small gaming spot during your day. Inside the box you&amp;rsquo;ll find a grid with 8 perforated spaces, 8 dice in 3 different colors, 32 Cog cards (16 normal difficulty, 16 higher difficulty), and gear tokens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/view.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;R.A.V.E.L. components overview&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. components overview&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set up, place the grid at the center of the table, then take the 8 dice and, in a random manner, take one die at a time, shake it, and place it on the grid. Take the 16 normal difficulty Cog cards for your first play, shuffle them and place 4 face-down on each side of the grid (top, bottom, left, right), then flip face-up the first card on each side. Finally, take 8 gear tokens for a normal difficulty game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/setup.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;R.A.V.E.L. setup ready to play&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. setup ready to play&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To win, you must solve all of the Cog cards. If you&amp;rsquo;re unable to solve cards due to a lack of tokens or available moves, you lose the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll manipulate the 8 dice on the grid to solve Cog cards placed around it. You have 8 gear tokens (at normal difficulty) that allow you to buy actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Cog card has a condition to be solved, such as having 2 dice of the same color on the card&amp;rsquo;s side, all 3 dice in sequential order, or all dice showing different numbers. When you solve a card, you gain a one-time effect that must be used immediately, if not used, it&amp;rsquo;s lost. These effects can include recovering tokens, modifying dice faces, moving dice, or moving cards around the grid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have two main actions available using gear tokens: move a die to an adjacent space (1 token), or change the face of a die (2 tokens). Beyond gear tokens, bonuses from solved cards allow you to further manipulate the grid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/solved-cards.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Cards with all conditions satisfied&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Cards with all conditions satisfied&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;difficulty-levels&#34;&gt;Difficulty Levels&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can make the game easier by starting with more than 8 gear tokens. To increase difficulty, add high-level Cog cards to the deck, the more you add, the harder the game becomes. You can play with all 16 high-level difficulty cards for the ultimate challenge. High-level cards add stricter conditions, such as sequential dice needing to be in ascending order, or same-color dice all showing even numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/example-of-cards.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Cards and their higher difficulty versions. Top row: for the basic card, the 3 dice must show the same number; for the higher difficulty card, the dice must also be different colors.&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Cards and their higher difficulty versions. Top row: for the basic card, the 3 dice must show the same number; for the higher difficulty card, the dice must also be different colors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played this game more than 10 times already. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested it by adding 4 high-level difficulty cards, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet managed to win at this difficulty level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The game is quick, fun, clever, and addictive. You have to carefully think about which card to solve first to take advantage of the bonuses, for example, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used any gear tokens yet, solving a card that allows you to retrieve tokens won&amp;rsquo;t let you use the bonus, so timing matters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251218-ravel/game-lost-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Final game state with 2 Cog cards unsolved&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Final game. 2 Cog cards not solved so game over 🥲&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;rating&#34;&gt;Rating&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 8 out of 10.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a small game, I rate it 8/10. I would have liked to see some kind of story or theme to make it more thematic. Besides that, I have nothing negative to say about the game. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent game to take with you on a trip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.A.V.E.L. is a perfect pocket puzzle game: quick to set up, quick to play, and endlessly replayable thanks to its variable difficulty. If you enjoy solo puzzle games that require careful planning and resource management, this is definitely worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played R.A.V.E.L.? What difficulty level have you tried? Have you managed to beat the highest difficulty?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/413248/ravel&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Board Game Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://inpatience.com/en/Games-47-RAVEL&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;inPatience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/z6qyu_oud4o?si=mLp62hpGEP8Dq9vV&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;One Stop Co-op Shop - great solo playthrough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Tracks: Siren Bay – Review</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Tracks: Siren Bay – Review&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Tracks: Siren Bay, a unique sound-based detective game that caught my attention with its innovative mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tracks: Siren Bay is a cooperative mystery game where you solve cases by listening to audio tracks and following suspects through a city map. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting twist on traditional detective games, though it has some limitations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tracks: Siren Bay is a 1–6 player game from 2022 with a playtime of 25–45 minutes for ages 12+. It was designed by Juan Rodriguez and Christian Rubiella, illustrated by Pierô, and published by KYF Edition (French version).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Tracks Siren Bay box&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Tracks: Siren Bay box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You play as freshly graduated police officers nicknamed &amp;ldquo;The Rockies.&amp;rdquo; Your first assignment is the Siren Bay Police Department. Upon arrival, Captain Mia Sanchez welcomes you and explains your role. Siren Bay is a quiet city with few issues, but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to track criminals using an old security system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your office is filled with security camera screens and an audio system. Due to humidity, only 4 cameras work simultaneously. This is where you&amp;rsquo;ll track criminals by listening to sound excerpts and checking camera footage when needed. &lt;strong&gt;Welcome to Siren Bay&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-components&#34;&gt;Game Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside the box you&amp;rsquo;ll find a large map of Siren Bay, a deck of cards representing security cameras, 15 cases to solve, the rulebook, and a QR code to download the companion app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/material.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Tracks Siren Bay components&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Game Components&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app is mandatory to play. The game is only published in a few languages, and English is not included.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/languages.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Available languages on app&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Available Languages on App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no traditional win or lose condition. The goal is to solve cases by correctly answering questions about the criminals&amp;rsquo; locations and activities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select a case from the 15 available — starting with Case 1 is recommended. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected the case in the app, start the audio track. During the first listening, you cannot rewind or advance the track. You need to listen carefully to identify the path followed by the suspects, kidnappers, drug dealers, and other criminals, using only the sounds you hear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The map provides visual clues: parks, churches, football stadiums, schools, and more. Some sounds are difficult to identify on their own. When needed, you can use security camera cards to check specific corners of the city. Is there a coffee shop on that corner? A baby crying? These cameras help clarify ambiguous sounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, you can only have 4 security cameras active at the same time. If you need to check another location, you must turn off one of the 4 cameras already in use. This limitation adds strategic thinking to which cameras you keep active and when to switch them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first listening, you&amp;rsquo;ll answer a question, usually &amp;ldquo;Where can we find the suspects?&amp;rdquo; You then select locations on the app&amp;rsquo;s map to send police units. If you&amp;rsquo;re correct, you solve the case or unlock additional questions. If wrong, you can make additional attempts. You can listen to the track as many times as needed before giving your answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/example.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Security cameras during case resolution&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Security cameras during case resolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251214-tracks/app.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;App audio system&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;App audio system&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What attracted me initially was solving mysteries using sound. It&amp;rsquo;s like a Sherlock Holmes game, but you follow an audio track instead of written clues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played 6 cases so far and enjoyed them all. I didn&amp;rsquo;t solve every case on my first try — the difficulty varies significantly. In some cases, I had to listen to the soundtrack a dozen times before spotting the correct path. It was challenging but fun, and I&amp;rsquo;m curious about what the remaining 9 cases have in store.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sound-quality&#34;&gt;Sound Quality&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sound quality is really good, which is essential for a game built entirely around audio clues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;variety-in-scenarios&#34;&gt;Variety in Scenarios&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One scenario required heavy reliance on security cameras to identify sounds: a coffee shop, a street band, a barking dog, a crying baby, an ice cream truck&amp;rsquo;s music. It was amusing to discover that suspects don&amp;rsquo;t always travel by car (easier to follow due to turn signals) — sometimes they use bicycles!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scenarios I&amp;rsquo;ve tested are quite variable with increasing difficulty, which keeps things interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparison-with-other-detective-games&#34;&gt;Comparison with Other Detective Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When compared to Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective, Sherlock is better with more complicated and intricate cases. The mysteries in Sherlock Holmes are more interesting overall. Even so, Tracks: Siren Bay has its own appeal thanks to its unique sound-based mechanism and its accessibility as a family game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;language-dependency&#34;&gt;Language Dependency&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is not heavily language-dependent, but you still need to understand some French (or whichever language version you have) to catch certain clues, like door numbers, &amp;ldquo;turn right&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;turn left&amp;rdquo; directions, or bits of conversation. In my case, the game is in French, and as a French speaker, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;player-count&#34;&gt;Player Count&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is really enjoyable solo. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it at higher player counts yet, but I imagine it would be fun. Everyone perceives sounds differently and has different sensitivities, which could lead to interesting discussions and collaborative problem-solving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;app-dependency--my-main-concern&#34;&gt;App Dependency – My Main Concern&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app dependency is the main reason for not giving a higher rating. I enjoyed the game, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like being dependent on technology for board games. I would have preferred if the audio could be downloadable or provided via a dedicated audio pen. Similarly, the case questions and solutions could have been provided in cards or a booklet format.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the app becomes unavailable or unsupported in the future, the game becomes completely unplayable. This is a significant concern for long-term ownership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;replayability&#34;&gt;Replayability&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After solving all 15 cases, the game has no replay value unless you forget the solutions. Once you know where the criminals are, there&amp;rsquo;s no mystery left to solve.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 7 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed playing Tracks: Siren Bay and trying to solve its mysteries. Using sound tracks is quite interesting and different from typical detective games. It&amp;rsquo;s accessible enough to be a family game and offers a unique experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the mandatory app dependency and limited replayability are significant drawbacks that prevent me from rating it higher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d recommend Tracks: Siren Bay to people who enjoy solving mysteries, want to try new mechanics, and don&amp;rsquo;t mind app-dependent games. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly good as a family game or for players new to detective games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Tracks: Siren Bay? What did you think of the sound-based mechanics? How many cases have you solved?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/370984/tracks-siren-bay&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kyf-edition.com/tracks/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;KYF Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/n400NqjnGhc?si=Vj5Jbjw93Den5lqJ&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Les Meeples – Tendances &amp;amp; Avis Jeux de Société&lt;/a&gt; – Great review of the game in French with playthrough&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Underwater Cities – Review</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Underwater Cities – Review&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my thoughts on Underwater Cities. It&amp;rsquo;s a card-driven worker placement game about building underwater civilizations. Despite some material quality issues, I really enjoyed this game and immediately wanted to play again after each session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Underwater Cities is a 2018 release for 1–4 players, ages 12+, with a playtime of 80–150 minutes. It was designed by Vladimír Suchý, illustrated by Milan Vavroň and Uildrim, and published by Delicious Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/underwater-cities-box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities box&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Underwater Cities box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Underwater Cities, players represent the world&amp;rsquo;s brightest minds, selected by the population to help humanity expand. Earth is overpopulated and we&amp;rsquo;re still four decades away from colonizing Mars (still trying to Terraform Mars in another board game 😝). With humanity&amp;rsquo;s rapid growth, underwater cities are the only way to expand our territory and accommodate everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll construct symbiotic cities and facilities to produce food and desalinate water, while creating laboratories to develop new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victory goes to whoever scores the most points. While you earn some points throughout the game via direct actions and production phases, the bulk of your score comes from end-game scoring with your cities, end-game scoring cards and tiles, plus remaining materials and money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup--components&#34;&gt;Setup &amp;amp; Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no insert in the box, meaning lots of plastic bags to store everything. This makes setup slow for a game that, with a proper insert, would take 5–8 minutes to set up. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent candidate for creating my own origami insert! 😝&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The material quality is disappointing compared to the gameplay quality. The tokens are poor-quality cardboard, and the player board is a thin sheet of paper. This game deserves better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/ressources.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities resources&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Resources&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/player-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities player board&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Player Board&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/player-aid.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities player aid&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Player Aid&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is essentially card placement based, divided into 3 eras with 3–4 rounds each. Each round, you perform 3 actions by placing a token in an available spot on the board, triggering an immediate action. There are 3 different action zones, each color-coded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When selecting an action, you must also play a card. If the colors match, you can execute the card&amp;rsquo;s action; otherwise, the card is discarded. For instance, if you place your token on a green action space and play a green card, you get both the board action AND the card effect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/play-an-action.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Action example&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Action example: Purple player blocks the actions with his token and plays a card. The player will be able to build a symbiotic city and resolve the effect of the card.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;card-types&#34;&gt;Card Types&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 different card types: immediate effect cards, permanent effect cards, cards with effects activated once per era when triggered on the board, production cards that activate at each era&amp;rsquo;s end, and end-game scoring cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are special cards that can include any of the above types but have a cost to play and offer more powerful effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/action-cards-zoom.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Different types of action cards&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Different types of cards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/special-cards.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Special cards with card back and cost&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Special cards with card back and cost&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the rounds, you&amp;rsquo;ll develop your cities by creating symbiotic cities (domes) and plants attached to those domes. Cities only become productive and count toward your network once connecting tunnels are built.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategic-combos&#34;&gt;Strategic Combos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game allows for satisfying combos. For example, you might have played an ongoing effect card that allows you to gain credits every time you upgrade a tunnel. Or you can play an action in the green zone that activates that specific action, and with the card effect, you can pay a credit to activate another action from a different zone. These combinations create powerful turns when properly planned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-opinion&#34;&gt;My Opinion&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solo game is a kind of BYOS. There&amp;rsquo;s no real automa, just a system that blocks your actions in a fixed pattern each round. To win, you need 7 connected cities and a score of 100 points or more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not usually a huge fan of BYOS games, but this one didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me. The game has a Terraforming Mars feel with its cards, tableau building, and combos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played twice so far, and I can already say the game is frustrating in the best way possible. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost both times, but instead of feeling defeated, I immediately want to play again. As soon as the game ends, I want to start over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/play.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Main board and card tableau from a player&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Main board and card tableau from a player&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparing-my-two-plays&#34;&gt;Comparing My Two Plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I definitely improved between games — my score went from 72 on the first play to 83 on the second. The experience felt completely different because the player boards are asymmetric and I chose a different one for my second game. The cards that came into play were also so different that I needed to adjust to a completely different strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I improved primarily by better utilizing the end-game scoring cards, special cards you can obtain using a specific action space. On my first play, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider those cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategic-depth&#34;&gt;Strategic Depth&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is really tight and each move must be carefully considered. During production phases, it seems like you&amp;rsquo;re producing lots of resources, but they&amp;rsquo;re never quite enough. You only have 3 production rounds in the entire game (one at the end of each era), and since you don&amp;rsquo;t play after the last production phase, you really only have 2 productive rounds. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to adjust your strategy based on the cards in your hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-tough-decision&#34;&gt;A Tough Decision&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, in my second play during my last round, I thought I would score better with a particular end-game scoring tile. I realized later that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fulfill its requirements. This happened because in my last round I focused on another strategy that wasn&amp;rsquo;t that effective — I wanted to do everything but couldn&amp;rsquo;t due to the lack of actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;expansions&#34;&gt;Expansions&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two expansions are available: New Discoveries (2019) and Data Era (2025).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Discoveries brings improvements that should have been in the base game, including dual-layer player boards. It also adds cards, assistants, starting resources, and a new museum mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Era introduces a new resource type — data discs — which provide additional actions along with new buildings called data centers and a new city type: information cities. These additions provide new scoring opportunities. This expansion also brings material improvements for upgraded facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t own either expansion yet, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested them. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to have to purchase expansions for better quality materials. Either way, the game is excellent, so I&amp;rsquo;ll most likely purchase them sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 8.5 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even without being a big fan of BYOS and despite the material quality issues, I will rate this game an 8.5/10. The game is really pleasant to play and really challenging. It&amp;rsquo;s an expert board game that deserves a place in any board gamer&amp;rsquo;s collection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was reluctant to try it at first due to its not-so-appealing appearance, but I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I tested it. I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Underwater Cities? What&amp;rsquo;s your experience with it? Do you own the expansions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/247763/underwater-cities&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deliciousgames.org/underwater-cities&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Delicious Games&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(rules available in several languages)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8WU2EcmEL2E?si=pxwwBjm5Ta_X1mSE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;3 Minute Board Games&lt;/a&gt; – Great quick review of the game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/6_HCzo_HAYI?si=K7JAiRZZD55G9t4n&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Underwater Cities Tutorial &amp;amp; Playthrough – JonGetsGames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Endless Winter: Paleoamericans – First Impressions</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Endless Winter: Paleoamericans – First Impressions&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I want to share my thoughts about my first game of Endless Winter: Paleoamericans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Endless Winter cover box&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Endless Winter cover box&#xA;          &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com&#34;&gt;via BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endless Winter is a 1–4 player game for ages 12+ with a playtime of 60–120 minutes. It was designed by Stan Kordonskiy and illustrated by Mihajlo Dimitrievski and Yoma, published by Fantasia Games. My copy is the Spanish edition of the base game published by TCG Factory, with the French expansions published by Matagot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-complete.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Endless Winter set up&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Endless Winter set up&#xA;          &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com&#34;&gt;via BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endless Winter takes place in North America around 10,000 BC. Players represent tribal chiefs leading their tribes across several generations to become the most prosperous. Throughout the game, tribes migrate and settle new lands, establish cultural traditions, hunt paleolithic megafauna, and build everlasting megalithic structures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endless Winter is a Euro-style game combining worker placement and deck building. Each round, players send tribe members to various action spaces and pay for actions by playing cards and spending resources. Tribe cards grant additional labor, while Culture cards provide unique effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cards can also be saved for the end-of-round Eclipse phase, where they&amp;rsquo;re simultaneously revealed to determine new player order and trigger bonus actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup--components&#34;&gt;Setup &amp;amp; Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setup time is considerable due to the many components, but the game&amp;rsquo;s insert is excellent and significantly reduces setup time. Everything has its place, no plastic bags with mixed-up pieces! The component quality is excellent, making everything pleasant to handle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-insert.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Endless Winter inserts&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Endless Winter inserts&#xA;          &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com&#34;&gt;via BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-first-play&#34;&gt;My First Play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my first game, I played the most basic setup without the two modules included in the base game, playing solo against the AI opponent using the normal difficulty setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first cycle was slower as I worked to understand the rules and iconography. The game is fully language-independent, and after one round, the iconography started making sense — I needed to reference the rules less and less.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solo opponent is challenging but really easy to manage. The rules were, in my opinion, very clear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay-experience&#34;&gt;Gameplay Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I definitely made some mistakes and didn&amp;rsquo;t use the best strategy, but it was a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love that cards can be used in multiple ways. Culture cards provide actions at the beginning of your phase, while Character cards boost your chosen actions from the player board.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme came through beautifully and the actions made sense. Boosting your action with a Character card represents sending help — so more workforce. If you hunt and send a Hunter as your booster, you gain more workforce than if you send a Crafter. It&amp;rsquo;s intuitive and thematic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After completing actions, you prepare for the Eclipse phase. Thematically, this makes perfect sense — people of that era believed eclipses were magical phenomena with mystical force that could be harnessed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Boards of Endless Winter&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Boards of Endeless Winter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-main-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Main Board with actions visible&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Main Board with actions visible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-player-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Player Boards - AI player above and human player below&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Player Boards - AI player above and human player below&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251205-endless-winter/endless-winter-map.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Map Board&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Map Board&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;action-variety&#34;&gt;Action Variety&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During your action phase, you have several options: hunt, hire new characters, obtain new Culture cards, or migrate on the map board. A well-selected action can create a cascade effect and lead to powerful combo rounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The Result&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite my mistakes, I came incredibly close, losing by just one point. Final score: 60 (AI) to 59 (me). So close, yet so far!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this game — it&amp;rsquo;s one I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to try for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One drawback: you need a large table for setup as the game has many small components. Having things more condensed on a single board would have been a plus for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to play more games and test all the expansions. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably return with another post after more plays to see if this first impression holds and how the replayability feels over time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you tested this game? What was your experience, and at what player count did you play?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/305096/endless-winter-paleoamericans&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fantasiaboardgames.com/?location=47&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Fantasia Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tcgfactory.com/en/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;TCG Factory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.matagot.com/en/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Matagot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Discovering VianaCon 2025</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Discovering VianaCon 2025&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VianaCon&lt;/strong&gt; is an annual board game convention held in Viana do Castelo, Portugal, strategically scheduled right after Essen Spiel. This year it took place on November 7–9. The event is organized by the association Artmatriz and is completely free to attend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/vianacon2025.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;vianacon2025&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;VianaCon 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-makes-vianacon-special&#34;&gt;What Makes VianaCon Special&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being scheduled after Essen means brand-new games are available to test, alongside an extensive game library. Several game stores set up booths, and publishers present new releases and even prototypes. The convention offers diverse activities including exhibitions, workshops, tournaments, game launches, and raffles. There are also non-gaming activities like a Peddy Paper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-first-convention-experience&#34;&gt;My First Convention Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was my first board game convention ever! Despite being a passionate gamer for years, I&amp;rsquo;d never had the opportunity before. I attended for 2 days and managed to participate in the Peddy Paper and play 5 different games:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat: Pedal to the Metal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finspan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the Footsteps of Darwin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fuse&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Last Minute&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-atmosphere&#34;&gt;The Atmosphere&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was impressed by the volunteers from Artmatriz who were always available to help with rules explanations. They had a clever flag system for tables — you could signal &amp;ldquo;I need rules help&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Player spot available.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I felt a bit lost at first, but the atmosphere was so warm and welcoming that I quickly felt comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/vianacon.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;vianacon-picture&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;VianaCon 2025 Space&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peddy-paper-adventure&#34;&gt;The Peddy Paper Adventure&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first activity we did was the Peddy Paper. Since we were only 2 people, we joined another pair to form a team. It was fantastic, we had so much fun! It was a great way to explore the city while meeting new people who share the same passion. Unfortunately, our team came in second place&amp;hellip; so close!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/peddy-paper-viana.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;peddy-paper-viana&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Viana do Castelo Sunset&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/peddy-paper-viana-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;peddy-paper-viana-2&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Wall in Viana do Castelo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-special-conversation-with-carolina-semrau&#34;&gt;A Special Conversation with Carolina Semrau&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful one-on-one conversation with Carolina Semrau, co-designer of Trash Travelers. It&amp;rsquo;s a cooperative game for 1–4 players where you embark on a journey to save the ocean. During your travels, you collect trash, rescue animals, meet experts, and create objects from the trash you&amp;rsquo;ve gathered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carolina was incredibly enthusiastic and generous with her time, speaking with just the two of us. We discussed the game in depth and talked about broader environmental issues. Unfortunately, time constraints prevented us from testing the game, but our conversation definitely sparked my curiosity to try it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/travel-trashers-cover.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;travel-trashers-cover&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;The Travel Trashers - Images via BoardGameGeek&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/travel-trashers-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;travel-trashers-board&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;The Travel Trashers - Images via BoardGameGeek&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-favorites&#34;&gt;My Favorites&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of all the games I played, I particularly loved Heat: Pedal to the Metal and In the Footsteps of Darwin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251203-vianacon/darwin.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;darwin&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;In the Footsteps of Darwin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my first convention experience, I&amp;rsquo;m really happy. It was fun, welcoming, and inspiring. I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly attend more conventions in the future, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be back at VianaCon next year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>November 2025 Plays</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-november-plays/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-november-plays/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post November 2025 Plays&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;November was a great gaming month! I managed to complete 16 plays across 13 different games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-november-plays/november2025-stats.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;November-2025-Stats&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;November 2025 Stats&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-november-plays/november2025-plays.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;November-2025-Plays&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;November 2025 Plays&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of these games, 5 were played at &lt;strong&gt;VianaCon&lt;/strong&gt; and aren&amp;rsquo;t part of my collection (I&amp;rsquo;ll share more about that event in a separate post). The rest were home plays.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;perseverance-castaway-chronicles--episode-1&#34;&gt;Perseverance: Castaway Chronicles – Episode 1&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A really engaging game combining dice placement and area majority mechanics. The premise has you defending your camp against dinosaur attacks. The solo mode features two AI opponents called the Dissidents, making for a challenging adversary. You need to carefully calculate your dice placements to maximize efficiency while anticipating what the Dissidents might do on their turns. Strategic planning is essential. I thoroughly enjoyed this one and will definitely play it again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;heat-pedal-to-the-metal&#34;&gt;Heat: Pedal to the Metal&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finally tried this at VianaCon after wanting to test it for ages. I was hesitant about the solo mode, so it never made it to my collection. I played at 2 players, and the push-your-luck mechanics and risk-taking elements are genuinely fun. Playing cautiously simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t work—it would drain all the excitement from the game! While I enjoyed it immensely, I suspect this game truly shines at higher player counts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-notable-games&#34;&gt;Other Notable Games&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed In the Footsteps of Darwin as an accessible, family-friendly game with straightforward rules. It&amp;rsquo;s light and entertaining, with beautiful illustrations and a helpful companion book explaining the different species depicted in the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finspan left me slightly disappointed, especially when compared to its predecessor, Wingspan. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find the same level of enjoyment, though I think it deserves another chance before I form a final opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-you&#34;&gt;What About You?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;How was your November? Which game did you most enjoy, or least enjoy, playing?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Welcome to Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Welcome to Marta&#39;s BG Corner&#34; /&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/serious-avatar.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Avatar&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This the first post of my first blog, and there&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to share with you! Let me start by explaining why I created this page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marta&amp;rsquo;s BG Corner&lt;/strong&gt; is a space dedicated to all things board games. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my opinions, recent plays, and everything that fuels my passion for this incredible hobby. I won&amp;rsquo;t be posting on a fixed schedule, just whenever I have something I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-about-me&#34;&gt;A Little About Me&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved board games. My family gave me games throughout my childhood, and playing cards, La Bonne Paye, and Monopoly were regular fixtures at home. But my true passion, and my collection, really began in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first purchase was Estoril, but the game that made me completely fall for the hobby was Pandemic Legacy: Season 1. Even today, after around 1,000 plays of various games, I still consider it my best gaming experience. It was tense, intense, and unforgettable.&#xA;Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve explored countless games across different mechanics. My favorites are Euro games and deckbuilders. I recently ranked my top games and was surprised to discover they&amp;rsquo;re all heavy board games!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/my-top-games-2025.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Top Games 2025&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;My Top Games of 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-playing-style&#34;&gt;My Playing Style&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, my gaming sessions look a bit different. I love taking my time to set up a game, dive deep into the rules, and really learn the mechanics before playing. I have no problem splitting a game across multiple sessions, I rarely have a full 2-hour block anyway! Currently, I have two games set up on two different tables: Endless Winter and Underwater Cities. Yes, two tables! Each one waiting for me to continue my adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s a bit about me and my board gaming journey. &lt;em&gt;What was the game that got YOU hooked on the hobby? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your stories!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
