<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Introduction on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/introduction/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Introduction on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>Welcome to Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Welcome to Marta&#39;s BG Corner&#34; /&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/serious-avatar.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Avatar&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This the first post of my first blog, and there&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to share with you! Let me start by explaining why I created this page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marta&amp;rsquo;s BG Corner&lt;/strong&gt; is a space dedicated to all things board games. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my opinions, recent plays, and everything that fuels my passion for this incredible hobby. I won&amp;rsquo;t be posting on a fixed schedule, just whenever I have something I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-about-me&#34;&gt;A Little About Me&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved board games. My family gave me games throughout my childhood, and playing cards, La Bonne Paye, and Monopoly were regular fixtures at home. But my true passion, and my collection, really began in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first purchase was Estoril, but the game that made me completely fall for the hobby was Pandemic Legacy: Season 1. Even today, after around 1,000 plays of various games, I still consider it my best gaming experience. It was tense, intense, and unforgettable.&#xA;Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve explored countless games across different mechanics. My favorites are Euro games and deckbuilders. I recently ranked my top games and was surprised to discover they&amp;rsquo;re all heavy board games!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251202-welcome/my-top-games-2025.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Top Games 2025&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;My Top Games of 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-playing-style&#34;&gt;My Playing Style&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, my gaming sessions look a bit different. I love taking my time to set up a game, dive deep into the rules, and really learn the mechanics before playing. I have no problem splitting a game across multiple sessions, I rarely have a full 2-hour block anyway! Currently, I have two games set up on two different tables: Endless Winter and Underwater Cities. Yes, two tables! Each one waiting for me to continue my adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s a bit about me and my board gaming journey. What was the game that got YOU hooked on the hobby? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your stories! Come share your thoughts on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@martasbgcorner/115646593928364296&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
