<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Vladimír Suchý on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/designers/vladim%C3%ADr-such%C3%BD/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Vladimír Suchý on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/designers/vladim%C3%ADr-such%C3%BD/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>Underwater Cities – Review</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Underwater Cities – Review&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my thoughts on Underwater Cities. It&amp;rsquo;s a card-driven worker placement game about building underwater civilizations. Despite some material quality issues, I really enjoyed this game and immediately wanted to play again after each session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Underwater Cities is a 2018 release for 1–4 players, ages 12+, with a playtime of 80–150 minutes. It was designed by Vladimír Suchý, illustrated by Milan Vavroň and Uildrim, and published by Delicious Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/underwater-cities-box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities box&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Underwater Cities box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Underwater Cities, players represent the world&amp;rsquo;s brightest minds, selected by the population to help humanity expand. Earth is overpopulated and we&amp;rsquo;re still four decades away from colonizing Mars (still trying to Terraform Mars in another board game 😝). With humanity&amp;rsquo;s rapid growth, underwater cities are the only way to expand our territory and accommodate everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll construct symbiotic cities and facilities to produce food and desalinate water, while creating laboratories to develop new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win&#34;&gt;How to Win&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victory goes to whoever scores the most points. While you earn some points throughout the game via direct actions and production phases, the bulk of your score comes from end-game scoring with your cities, end-game scoring cards and tiles, plus remaining materials and money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup--components&#34;&gt;Setup &amp;amp; Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no insert in the box, meaning lots of plastic bags to store everything. This makes setup slow for a game that, with a proper insert, would take 5–8 minutes to set up. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent candidate for creating my own origami insert! 😝&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The material quality is disappointing compared to the gameplay quality. The tokens are poor-quality cardboard, and the player board is a thin sheet of paper. This game deserves better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/ressources.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Underwater Cities resources&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Resources&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 1rem; align-items: flex-start; justify-content: center; width: 100%; padding-right: 6rem; padding-left: 6rem;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/player-board.jpg&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;Underwater Cities player board&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;          &lt;p&gt;Player Board&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/player-aid.jpg&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;Underwater Cities player aid&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;          &lt;p&gt;Player Aid&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is essentially card placement based, divided into 3 eras with 3–4 rounds each. Each round, you perform 3 actions by placing a token in an available spot on the board, triggering an immediate action. There are 3 different action zones, each color-coded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When selecting an action, you must also play a card. If the colors match, you can execute the card&amp;rsquo;s action; otherwise, the card is discarded. For instance, if you place your token on a green action space and play a green card, you get both the board action AND the card effect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/play-an-action.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Action example&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Action example: Purple player blocks the actions with his token and plays a card. The player will be able to build a symbiotic city and resolve the effect of the card.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;card-types&#34;&gt;Card Types&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 different card types: immediate effect cards, permanent effect cards, cards with effects activated once per era when triggered on the board, production cards that activate at each era&amp;rsquo;s end, and end-game scoring cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are special cards that can include any of the above types but have a cost to play and offer more powerful effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 1rem; align-items: flex-start; justify-content: center; width: 100%; padding-right: 6rem; padding-left: 6rem;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/action-cards-zoom.jpg&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;Different types of action cards&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;          &lt;p&gt;Different types of cards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/special-cards.jpg&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;Special cards with card back and cost&#34; width=&#34;325&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;          &lt;p&gt;Special cards with card back and cost&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the rounds, you&amp;rsquo;ll develop your cities by creating symbiotic cities (domes) and plants attached to those domes. Cities only become productive and count toward your network once connecting tunnels are built.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategic-combos&#34;&gt;Strategic Combos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game allows for satisfying combos. For example, you might have played an ongoing effect card that allows you to gain credits every time you upgrade a tunnel. Or you can play an action in the green zone that activates that specific action, and with the card effect, you can pay a credit to activate another action from a different zone. These combinations create powerful turns when properly planned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-opinion&#34;&gt;My Opinion&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solo game is a kind of BYOS. There&amp;rsquo;s no real automa, just a system that blocks your actions in a fixed pattern each round. To win, you need 7 connected cities and a score of 100 points or more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not usually a huge fan of BYOS games, but this one didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me. The game has a Terraforming Mars feel with its cards, tableau building, and combos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played twice so far, and I can already say the game is frustrating in the best way possible. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost both times, but instead of feeling defeated, I immediately want to play again. As soon as the game ends, I want to start over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20251211-underwater-cities/play.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Main board and card tableau from a player&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Main board and card tableau from a player&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparing-my-two-plays&#34;&gt;Comparing My Two Plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I definitely improved between games — my score went from 72 on the first play to 83 on the second. The experience felt completely different because the player boards are asymmetric and I chose a different one for my second game. The cards that came into play were also so different that I needed to adjust to a completely different strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I improved primarily by better utilizing the end-game scoring cards, special cards you can obtain using a specific action space. On my first play, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider those cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategic-depth&#34;&gt;Strategic Depth&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is really tight and each move must be carefully considered. During production phases, it seems like you&amp;rsquo;re producing lots of resources, but they&amp;rsquo;re never quite enough. You only have 3 production rounds in the entire game (one at the end of each era), and since you don&amp;rsquo;t play after the last production phase, you really only have 2 productive rounds. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to adjust your strategy based on the cards in your hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-tough-decision&#34;&gt;A Tough Decision&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, in my second play during my last round, I thought I would score better with a particular end-game scoring tile. I realized later that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fulfill its requirements. This happened because in my last round I focused on another strategy that wasn&amp;rsquo;t that effective — I wanted to do everything but couldn&amp;rsquo;t due to the lack of actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;expansions&#34;&gt;Expansions&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two expansions are available: New Discoveries (2019) and Data Era (2025).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Discoveries brings improvements that should have been in the base game, including dual-layer player boards. It also adds cards, assistants, starting resources, and a new museum mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Era introduces a new resource type — data discs — which provide additional actions along with new buildings called data centers and a new city type: information cities. These additions provide new scoring opportunities. This expansion also brings material improvements for upgraded facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t own either expansion yet, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested them. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to have to purchase expansions for better quality materials. Either way, the game is excellent, so I&amp;rsquo;ll most likely purchase them sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 8.5 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even without being a big fan of BYOS and despite the material quality issues, I will rate this game an 8.5/10. The game is really pleasant to play and really challenging. It&amp;rsquo;s an expert board game that deserves a place in any board gamer&amp;rsquo;s collection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was reluctant to try it at first due to its not-so-appealing appearance, but I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I tested it. I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Underwater Cities? What&amp;rsquo;s your experience with it? Do you own the expansions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/247763/underwater-cities&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;BoardGameGeek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deliciousgames.org/underwater-cities&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Delicious Games&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(rules available in several languages)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8WU2EcmEL2E?si=pxwwBjm5Ta_X1mSE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;3 Minute Board Games&lt;/a&gt; – Great quick review of the game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/6_HCzo_HAYI?si=K7JAiRZZD55G9t4n&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Underwater Cities Tutorial &amp;amp; Playthrough – JonGetsGames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
