<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Welcome to the Moon on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/games/welcome-to-the-moon/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Welcome to the Moon on Marta&#39;s BG Corner</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/games/welcome-to-the-moon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>January 2026 Plays</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post January 2026 Plays&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m bringing you my plays from January. This month had fewer total plays but more depth with individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2026 by the Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11 plays (compared to 17 in December)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 different games&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 new-to-me games&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most played: Welcome to the Moon (5 plays)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life was busy this month, which resulted in fewer plays overall. However, I enjoyed focusing more deeply on individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/games-stats-january.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;BG Stats of January&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;BG Stats of January&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-games-discovered&#34;&gt;New Games Discovered&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;wayfarers-of-the-south-tigris--1-play&#34;&gt;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/wayfarers.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – Setup&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Wayfarers of the South Tigris – Setup&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are brave explorers, cartographers, and astronomers setting out from Baghdad to map the surrounding lands, sea, and sky. This 1-4 player game mixes several mechanics: worker placement, dice worker placement, set collection, and tile placement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this first play, particularly the construction of the panorama, the possible combos, and the need for medium to long-term planning. These elements create satisfying strategic depth and give you goals to work toward across multiple rounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I found the rulebook confusing. At first glance, it seems well-written, but when actually playing, I had difficulties finding answers to my questions. After a closer look, the rulebook organization feels muddled, making it hard to reference during play. I needed to return to the rules several times, which disrupted the flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I need to replay at least 2 more times before forming a complete opinion, but the core gameplay shows promise despite the rulebook issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;numbsters--1-play&#34;&gt;Numbsters – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/numbsters.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Numbsters – End of Game&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Numbsters – End of Game&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A solo small game that&amp;rsquo;s perfect to carry anywhere. No table space needed, you can hold the cards in your hand! The theme is &amp;ldquo;Hungry Numbers,&amp;rdquo; and it consists entirely of cards with beautifully designed numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal is to end with only the number 8 and one other card remaining. Crucially, the 8 must never be on top (the right side), you need the other card on top at the end, otherwise you lose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works: At the start of each round, you can either move one card or use the power of the rightmost card (or top card if holding them in your hand).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Eating Mechanic:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though it seems counterintuitive, smaller numbers eat bigger numbers! For a card to be eaten, the numbers must be sequential with the mouth card (the 8) in the middle. For example, if you have card 4, followed by 8, followed by 5, the 5 will be eaten because 4-5 are sequential around the 8.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 8 can never be eaten. However, if the 8 ends up on the right side (or on top when holding cards), you lose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Card Powers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Card powers can change the eating rules, some eat the smallest card, others the biggest, some target even numbers, etc. When using a power, you still need to eat a card adjacent to the 8, but the card whose power you&amp;rsquo;re using doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be adjacent, it just needs to be on the right side (or on top). After using a power, that card moves to the back (or left side).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked my first test. It&amp;rsquo;s really quick, easy to set up, and creates an interesting spatial puzzle. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bestseller, but I can see a lot of potential for travel or couch plays when you want a quick mental challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-i-continued-exploring&#34;&gt;Games I Continued Exploring&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;par-odin--1-play&#34;&gt;Par Odin – 1 play&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/par-odin.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Par Odin&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Par Odin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a board game properly speaking, but rather a puzzle game. You have a set of figures represented by the sides of dice, and you need to split the dice into two groups where the sum of each group is equal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each character has different values and effects. For example, the ring removes 1 point from its group, while the mage has no point value itself but equals the sum of all white dice (non-mages) in the same group. These special effects add layers of complexity to what seems like a simple balancing puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really like this game when I want something quick that makes me think. The puzzles are satisfying to solve, and the special character abilities keep things interesting across different challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-moon--5-plays&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Moon – 5 plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/welcome-to-the-moon.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to The Moon – Adventure 4&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to The Moon – Adventure 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I played this 5 times this month and will probably continue. As I mentioned in my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/&#34; &gt;dedicated review&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign side with different scenarios telling a cohesive story is really enjoyable. The increasing difficulty is also very pleasant, keeping each adventure challenging and fresh. The narrative progression from ship preparation through to lunar mining operations continues to engage me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;merchants-cove--3-plays&#34;&gt;Merchants Cove – 3 plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260208-january-plays/merchants-cove.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Merchants Cove and The Chronomancer with his assistant&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Merchants Cove and The Chronomancer with his assistant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An asymmetric game where each player is a merchant creating and selling merchandise to people arriving in the city by boat. There are 4 types of customers who can request 2 different types of goods: biggest or smallest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solo Mode:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solo mode uses an automa managed by a set of cards. The goal is to beat the automa&amp;rsquo;s score, creating a competitive challenge even when playing alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merchants Tested:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyable testing each merchant. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested 6 merchants over time, I still have 5 to try! In solo mode, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested 3 merchants: the Alchemist, the Blacksmith, and the Chronomancer with his assistant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed playing each one, with the Chronomancer being my favorite of these three. He has the most creative mechanics, you travel across time and collect artifacts. You need to coordinate the two characters available as they have some constraints that create interesting puzzle moments. Managing both the Chronomancer and his assistant adds a unique strategic layer not present in the other merchants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write a full review for this game once I&amp;rsquo;ve tested more merchants and can speak comprehensively about the variety they offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-ahead-to-february&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead to February&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260113-2025-plays/&#34; &gt;December 2025 year-in-review&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned wanting to play Tapestry, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible in January. It will probably be played during the next month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of fun with these games and will certainly play them again soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What were your most-played games in January? Are you exploring games deeply or trying lots of new ones?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item><item>
            <title>Welcome to the Moon: A Flip &amp; Write Campaign</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/</guid>
            <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34; alt=&#34;Featured image of post Welcome to the Moon: A Flip &amp; Write Campaign&#34; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m taking you on a journey to the moon! Let me introduce you to &lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Moon&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a flip &amp;amp; write game with 8 interconnected adventures that can be played standalone or as a campaign. With reusable sheets and compact design, it offers tremendous replayability in a small package. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re preparing starships, programming flight paths, or establishing lunar colonies, each adventure brings unique challenges and mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-overview&#34;&gt;Game Overview&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a 2021 release for 1-6 players, ages 10+, with a playtime of 25-30 minutes. The game was designed by Alexis Allard and Benoit Turpin, illustrated by Anne Heidsieck, and published by Blue Cocker Games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/box.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to the Moon box&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Box&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Welcome to the Moon, we&amp;rsquo;re called to colonize the moon as Earth is in bad shape. To succeed, we must first prepare our starship, program our path, and establish our lunar colony.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-it&#34;&gt;What Is It?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon is a flip &amp;amp; write game, you reveal cards (flipping them from a deck) and write numbers on your personal sheet based on what you draw. The twist? There are 8 different adventures, each with unique sheet designs and special rules, that can be played standalone or linked together in a campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The adventure guide has two modes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning mode&lt;/strong&gt; – Guides you through each adventure, as each has unique rules. The core mechanics remain the same, but the sheet designs mean numbers are placed differently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Campaign mode&lt;/strong&gt; – A connected narrative where each result influences the next adventure. Cards are hidden and revealed during gameplay, creating an evolving story.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-1.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 1&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;End of Adventure 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;components&#34;&gt;Components&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game includes 24 double-sided sheets (6 sheets with 2 scenarios each), 6 dry-erase pencils, starship cards, achievement cards, an adventure book with flavor text and setup instructions, and solo-specific cards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/components.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Welcome to the Moon components&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Components&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;component-quality&#34;&gt;Component Quality&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major plus: instead of paper pads, the game uses reusable sheets compatible with dry-erase markers. This keeps the box compact and allows unlimited replays. The internal organizers are fantastic, keeping everything well organized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/sheets.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Erasable sheets&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Erasable Sheets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/organizers.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Box organizers&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Organizers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-plays&#34;&gt;How It Plays&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each round, you reveal cards showing number-action pairs. Choose one pair, write the number on your sheet following the adventure&amp;rsquo;s placement rules, then optionally use the action. Actions include robots for building connections, water/plants for resources, energy for boosting effects, astronauts for modifying numbers (-2 to +2), and planning for strategic crosses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brilliance is in the tension: which number-action combo serves your immediate needs versus long-term strategy? Do you grab the perfect number but weak action, or the action you desperately need with an awkward number? Every choice matters because you&amp;rsquo;re racing toward three objectives while avoiding system errors that could end your game prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The game continues until someone completes all 3 objectives, fills every space on their sheet, or crosses all system errors. These conditions apply to both solo and multiplayer modes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;adventure-variety&#34;&gt;Adventure Variety&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed through Adventures 1-4 is a steady increase in difficulty and the introduction of new mechanics. The theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t change but evolves beautifully, starting from ship preparation (Adventure 1), progressing through the journey to the moon, arrival, and beginning mining operations (Adventure 4).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, Adventure 4 introduces mining as a two-step process: first entering numbers, then extracting resources by completing columns. Each adventure builds on the previous one while adding its own twist, creating a cohesive narrative of lunar colonization. The 8 adventures together form a complete story of establishing humanity&amp;rsquo;s presence on the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;campaign-mode&#34;&gt;Campaign Mode&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The campaign mode is where Welcome to the Moon truly shines. You score points at each scenario based on whether you accomplished objectives. You track your progress on a sheet included at the end of the campaign book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished the campaign yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing that satisfying feeling of having more points than the automa. However, each new scenario is more complicated and offers more points for completion, so the challenge intensifies. There are branching scenarios, in the first campaign part, these determine which 3 missions appear in each adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The full campaign requires at least 16 plays (8 adventures × 2 campaign parts). It&amp;rsquo;s easily replayed and simple to reset, making it perfect for multiple campaign runs or teaching new players.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/setup-adventure-3.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Setup for Adventure 3&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Setup for Adventure 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;solo-mode&#34;&gt;Solo Mode&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In solo play, you draw 3 cards from a single deck each round. Select 2 cards, one for the number, one for the action, and give the remaining card to the automa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At game end, the automa scores by summing cards of each type and multiplying by a level-specific multiplier. When mission cards are drawn, you follow AI-specific actions (usually crossing bonuses from your board to simulate multiplayer competition).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When all cards are drawn, reshuffle the discard pile (excluding automa cards). Mission cards are shuffled into the entire deck for subsequent draws.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/automa.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Automa cards&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Automa Cards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-curve&#34;&gt;Learning Curve&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules are simple, straightforward, and require no constant rulebook reference, everything flows smoothly. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taught it to anyone yet, but I estimate 5-10 minutes would be sufficient to explain the core concepts. Each adventure&amp;rsquo;s unique rules are clearly explained and easy to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparison-to-other-flip-and-writes&#34;&gt;Comparison to Other Flip-and-Writes&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t played the original Welcome To…, so I can&amp;rsquo;t compare directly. However, when comparing with other flip-and-writes like &lt;strong&gt;Demeter&lt;/strong&gt;, Welcome to the Moon stands out as more complete due to its story dimension. The campaign structure and narrative progression elevate it beyond typical flip &amp;amp; write experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing through the campaign and just finished mission 4, mission 5 is next. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet started the second campaign part with the hidden narrative cards, as I&amp;rsquo;m still working through the learning portion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost only once to the AI and won 3 times. It&amp;rsquo;s been a real pleasure moving through the different adventures and reading the story. The adventures have a logical progression that makes thematic sense and keeps me eager for the next challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-2.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 2&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Adventure 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/posts/20260124-welcome-to-the-moon/end-of-adventure-4.jpg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;End of Adventure 4&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;Adventure 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros-and-cons&#34;&gt;Pros and Cons&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I Love:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excellent variability and replayability through 8 distinct adventures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Campaign mode adds meaningful narrative progression&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reusable sheets are environmentally friendly and space-efficient&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simple rules that flow smoothly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Satisfying strategic tension in every card choice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Great organization inside the box&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quick playtime (25-30 minutes) perfect for multiple sessions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Holds It Back:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While excellent, I suspect replayability will diminish after completing the campaign&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flip &amp;amp; write mechanics, while well-executed here, aren&amp;rsquo;t my absolute favorite genre&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The game creates that &amp;ldquo;one more play&amp;rdquo; urge during the campaign, but I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain about long-term replay value once the story is complete&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 9 out of 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Moon successfully captures the excitement of lunar colonization in an accessible flip &amp;amp; write format. The 8 adventures provide significant variety, the campaign mode adds compelling narrative depth, and the reusable sheets are an excellent design choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is probably one of my favorite flip-and-writes. It&amp;rsquo;s quick to play, easy to set up, and the campaign structure gives it staying power that most flip-and-writes lack. The steady difficulty progression and introduction of new mechanics keep each adventure fresh and challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy flip-and-writes and want one with excellent replayability, a compelling campaign, and meaningful strategic decisions, Welcome to the Moon is highly recommended. Even if flip-and-writes aren&amp;rsquo;t typically your favorite, the narrative structure and adventure variety make this worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-turn&#34;&gt;Your Turn&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you played Welcome to the Moon? Which adventure is your favorite? How far have you gotten in the campaign? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your experiences!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/339789/welcome-to-the-moon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Board Game Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bluecocker.com/en/landing-page/#post-987&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Blue Cocker Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/yvB3RR7xxwQ?si=YIaDCTnuaXu1dqSX&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Solooperative Games&lt;/a&gt; - Solo playthrough of the Adventure 1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
